cyrillus.com 2017-11-21

# Private life

Cyrillus undertakes to protect the privacy of persons using its website, as well as the confidentiality of the supplied personal information. 

  * 1\. Identity of the data controller
  * 2\. Collection and processing of your data
  * 3\. Payment security
  * 4\. Cookies
  * 5\. Social networks

## 1\. IDENTITY OF THE DATA CONTROLLER 

The data are collected by CYRILLUS SAS, which is responsible for their processing  
Head office: 1 chaussée de la Muette 75016 PARIS - FRANCE  
Paris TCR B.421.022.997  
SAS (simplified joint stock company) with capital of 6,593,400 euros  
Chairman: SAEGUAJ SAS, represented by Thierry JAUGEAS 

## 2\. COLLECTION AND PROCESSING OF YOUR DATA 

### 2.1 Collection 

The personal information that you provide when placing an order are only used in order to personalize your browsing experience on our website, as well to ensure the correct processing of your order, fight against fraud, deliver products, carry out payment transactions and contact you about your orders.   
We also use this information for statistical purposes.  
As such, by providing us with your e-mail, you will receive a confirmation of your order. 

When you visit our site, we may request information by means of questionnaires, forms and notably when you create your customer account. Marked by an asterisk, the requested data are mandatory. They are required in order to process your requests. In case of non-response, CYRILLUS will not be able to respond to your requests. Intended to help us learn more about you, any other information is optional. You are not required to respond. 

When browsing our website, information about your browsing is likely to be recorded via “Cookies” files installed on your terminal, in order to allow us to offer you customized offers, adapted to your 'interests. You may refuse the installation of cookies as described below. 

### 2.2 Commercial offers

CYRILLUS shall send you adequate offers and good deals by e-mail, SMS, and mobile if you opted for this, and by ordinary mail if you did not opt out when submitting your information.   
In addition, if you place an order and have not previously expressed your wish not to receive commercial prospecting, we will nevertheless use your email in order to send you commercial offers for products similar to those ordered.  
Should CYRILLUS send out prospecting e-mails, the sender CYRILLUS will be clearly identified and the nature of the commercial proposal will be indicated in the subject line. At the end of each message, you will be able to unsubscribe from our prospecting e-mails by means of a simple click. 

### 2.3 Recipient of data

he collected information are destinated at CYRILLUS SAS, the data controller. 

Certain data, in particular personal data, may be communicated in a secure way to technical partners linked to CYRILLUS by contract for the execution of subcontracted tasks necessary for the management of your account, the execution of your orders, delivery of goods and services, the fight against fraud, the making of payments, certain aspects of after-sales service or to carry out satisfaction surveys. 

In addition, unless you object to the collection of your data, the information concerning you may be communicated to the business partners of CYRILLUS SAS (including the other companies of the group CYRILLUS-VERTBAUDET GROUP) who will be able to send you their commercial offers by mail (we do not communicate to partners the fixed telephone number).  
They will be able to send you their offers by email if you have explicitly accepted it. 

### 2.4 Combating fraud

In order to ensure the security of payments during on-site transactions, avoid fraud and thus protect consumers in the context of distance selling, CYRILLUS has put in place the necessary anti-fraud measures and can to carry out automated processing of some of your personal data, the purpose of which is to control, or cause to be checked by its subcontractors, the orders placed on the website in order to verify the regularity of the information transmitted to it. 

Therefore, if an order does not provide all the guarantees necessary to ensure a safe and secure payment, CYRILLUS reserves the right to cancel the order or ask you for additional information and documents in order to validate the order. 

### 2.5 Hosting your personal data

CYRILLUS is present in different countries but your personal data is only stored on secure servers located in France. 

Nevertheless, in order to perform certain services, CYRILLUS may have to make your data transit through servers that can be located all over the world or give access to personal data to providers located abroad. 

CYRILLUS will naturally take appropriate measures to maintain the security of personal information during the transfer and upon receipt of such information. Subcontractors and contractors will be bound by contract with CYRILLUS, which will incorporate standard contractual clauses (as published by the European Commission). CYRILLUS also requires its subcontractors and service providers to guarantee a level of security, confidentiality and adequate protection of privacy and fundamental rights. 

### 2.6 Your Rights

In accordance with article 34 of the French «Information technology and freedoms» law of 6 January 1978, you have the right to access, modify, rectify and delete data concerning you. In order to exercise this right, you may write to:   
CYRILLUS  
Web Client Relationship  
216 Rue Winoc Chocqueel  
59200 Tourcoing  
France

Do not forget to mention all your contact details (name, first name, address, email and if possible customer number ...) so that we can do the necessary as soon as possible. 

You can also make your request by email on www.cyrillus.com, under the heading "Contact us" 

At any time, you can also access and change the information pertaining to your contact details in your customer area under the “my customer area” heading, and manage your newsletters under the “contact details” heading, or by writing to us at the above address. 

## 3\. PAYMENT SECURITY

We are committed to ensuring the security of your personal data via strict procedures in our company. For data collected on the website, we use the secure SSL protocol (Secure Socket Layer) which guarantees a high level of protection. 

To ensure payment security, CYRILLUS uses the services of PCI-DSS-certified providers. This standard is an international security standard whose objectives are to ensure the confidentiality and integrity of cardholder data, thereby securing card and transaction data protection. 

When you pay by credit card, our ordering system connects in real time with the system of our payment service providers, which collects your data and performs various checks to avoid abuse and fraud. The data is stored on the servers of these payment providers and is not transmitted on CYRILLUS servers at any time. 

Thus, when you enter your card number (credit card), authorization searches are automatically transmitted in encrypted mode. The authorizations and data are then checked with your bank to avoid abuses and fraud. 

During your payment, you have the possibility to save the details of your credit card to facilitate your future purchases on the website. This information is thus recorded and secured with our partners subject to the PCI-DSS (Payment Card Industry Data Security Standard). You can view the list of your saved cards (in hidden mode), but also delete all or part of its contents. 

In order to debit the account during billing or credit following a return, our payment providers keep the bank details associated with the authorization number, the time required to complete the transaction and the processing of any claims (returns, litigation). 

##  4\. COOKIES 

When visiting our site, information relative to your browsing on our site may be recorded in “Cookies” stored on your device (computer, tablet, smartphone, etc.).  
We install these cookies in order to ensure that you are more easily able to browse our site. Cookies can also be installed by our partners in order to customise the advertising offer that may be made to you outside of the cyrillus.com site. 

### 4.1 Cyrillus cookies

When you connect to our site www.cyrillus.com, we may – based on your choices regarding your browser’s configuration – install various cookies on your device 

  * Analytical cookies, which aim to establish attendance statistics (number of visits, page views, abandonment in the order process, etc.) in order to monitor and improve the quality of our services.
  * Cookies strictly necessary, the objective of which is to adapt the presentation of our website to the preferences of display of your terminal, to keep your basket, etc.
  * Functional cookies to:  
Storing information entered in forms, managing and securing access to personal and placeholders such as your account, managing your shopping cart.  
Provide you with content, including advertising, related to your interests and personalize the offers we send you. 

### 4.2 Third party cookies

When you access our site, one or more cookies may be stored in your computer via the pages on our site or via the content displayed in our advertising spaces.  
Either from the advertiser of the advertising content in question, or a company other than the advertiser (advertising agency, audience measurement company, targeted advertising service provider, etc.), that has associated a cookie with an advertiser’s advertising content. 

If relevant, the cookies created by these third parties will allow them, for as long as these cookies remain valid:  

  * to record the number of times that the advertising content displayed in our advertising spaces has been displayed, to identify the displayed advertisements, the number of users who clicked on each ad, to calculate the sums owed as a result, and to calculate statistics (analytical cookies);
  * to recognise your device during your subsequent browsing on any other site or service on which these advertisers or third parties have also created cookies and, if relevant, to adapt these third party sites and services or the advertisements that they display, to the browsing parameters of your device that they may recognise (adverstising cookies). 

These are the cookies used to present you advertisements or to send you information adapted to your interests on our website or outside our website when browsing the internet.  
The creation and use of cookies by third parties are subject to the policies of these third parties regarding the protection of privacy. We cannot access or control such third party cookies. However, we ensure that the partner companies process the information collected via our site in compliance with the “Information technology and freedoms” law. 

### 4.3 Your choice regarding cookies

#### a) The choices available to you through your browser

You can configure your browser so that cookies will be installed in your device or, on the contrary, in order to block them, either systematically or according to their issuer. You can also configure your browser so that you will be asked to accept or refuse the installation of cookies before a cookie is installed in your device.  
Please note that if your browser is configured to refuse all cookies, you will not be able to make any purchases or take advantage of our site’s essential functions, such as storing items in your basket or receiving customised recommendations. We ask you to configure your browser appropriately.  
Each browser’s configuration is different. It is described in your browser’s help menu, where you can find out how to modify your choice with regard to cookies. 

For information here are the modalities for the main browsers: 

  * **If you are using the Internet Explorer browser**
    1. From the Tools menu, select "Internet Options"
    2. Click the Privacy tab. You will see privacy settings with six options, which allow you to control the number of cookies that will be saved: Block All Cookies, High, Medium High, Medium (Default Level), Low, And Accept All Cookies
  *  **If you are using the Mozilla Firefox browser**
    1. On the Tools menu, select "Options"
    2. Select the Privacy tab in the Options window
    3. From the drop-down menu, choose "Use Custom Settings for History". This will bring up the options for the cookies and you can choose to allow or deny them by checking the appropriate box.
  *  **If you are using the Safari browser**
    1. In your browser, choose Edit> Preferences
    2. Click Security
    3. Click Show Cookies
    4. Select the option you want in the "Accept cookies" section
  *  **If you are using the Google Chrome browser**
    1. From the Settings menu, select "Show advanced settings" at the bottom of the page.
    2. Click the "Content Settings" button in the Confidentiality section
    3. The section at the top of the page that appears then tells you more about cookies and allows you to install the cookies you want. It also allows you to delete the currently stored cookies.

#### b) Your choices expressed online via inter-professional platforms

You can contact the Youronlinechoices site, created by the digital advertising professionals that are members of the European association EDAA (European Digital Advertising Alliance) and managed in France by the Interactive Advertising Bureau France. This European platform is shared by hundreds of Internet-based advertising professionals, and it serves as a centralised interface through which you can express your refusal or acceptance of the cookies that are used to adapt advertisements to your device’s browsing (http://www.youronlinechoices.com/uk/your-ad-choices). Please note that this procedure will not prevent advertising from being displayed on the Internet sites that you visit. It will only block the technologies that are used to tailor the advertising to your areas of interest. 

#### c) Flash”© cookies for the “Adobe Flash Player”

“Adobe Flash Player”™ is a computer application that is used for the development of dynamic content using the “Flash” computer language. Flash (and applications of the same type) record the settings, preferences and usage of such content by means of technology that is similar to cookies. However, “Adobe Flash Player”™ manages such information and your choices via a different interface than the one provided by your web browser.  
If your device is likely to display content developed using the Flash language, we suggest that you access your tools for managing Flash cookies directly on the Adobe website: http://www.adobe.com. (Cookies tab) 

#### d) Third party cookies from our website

When you access our website, the following partners can deposit cookies on your browser and collect other technical information about your navigation to serve you with ads that are relevant to your interests on any interactive medium (web, mobile application, e-mail). To learn more or to oppose it you can consult their respective privacy charter. The refusal of these cookies does not have any impact on the use of our website. However, refusing advertising cookies will not stop advertising on our website or on the Internet.  
This will only display an advertisement that will not reflect your interests or preferences. 

Our site uses computer applications created by third parties, which allow the web surfer to share our site’s content with other persons or to provide these other persons with their opinions regarding some of our site’s content. This is notably the case of the “Share” and “Like” buttons used by social networks such as Facebook, “Google+”, “Twitter”, etc.  
When the customer visits a site page containing such a button, the web browser establishes a direct connection with the social network’s servers.  
If the customer is connected to the social network while browsing, the application buttons can be used to link the visited pages to his or her user account.   
If the customer interacts by means of plug-ins, for example by clicking on the “Like” button for leaving a comment, the corresponding information will be sent to the social network and published via his/her account.  
If the customer does not want the social network to link the information connected via Cyrillus to his/her user account, s/he must disconnect from the social network before visiting the CYRILLUS site.  
Please consult the privacy protection policies of these social networks in order to review the intended usage, notably for advertising purposes, of the browsing information that they collect by means of these application buttons.
